?Opening Song ?
[Roars]
Get out of there, Galliard!
[EREN TITAN grunting]
[Roars]
[KOSLOW] Direct hit
on the Founding Titan!
It's stopped moving!
One down.
Now let's put another
in the Beast.
[FLOCH]
We can't let them fire!
Would you piss off already?
The Cart Titan is still up!
We can't win this fight
unless we deal with her!
[MIKASA]
Armin!
[MARLEYAN SOLDIER 78A groans]
[MARLEYAN SOLDIERS gasp]
[CONNY]
Enemy's holed up in the houses!
[JEAN]
Fall back! That way's no good!
Can't take out the cart till
we've dealt with those soldiers.
I know.
[PYXIS]
Circle around them!
We'll strike the enemy
from behind!
Think Pyxis has
the right idea.
We don't have enough firepower
to risk a full-frontal assault.
We need to attack them
from the rear.
[MARLEYAN SOLDIERS scream]
[ZEKE]
I fell? I'm on the ground.
Did I get shot?
[ZEKE]
Eren.
Wake up, Porco!
[REINER] We're so close.
Find your strength!
[MARCEL]
I'm sorry.
Listen Reiner.
The truth of it is,
you were never
supposed to be chosen.
[MARCEL]
I influenced the army's decision
by making my little
brother look bad,
and putting you
up on a pedestal.
[MARCEL] Sorry. I only did it
so that he would be safe.
[PIECK TITAN]
General Magath!
[MAGATH]
Zeke's moving? He survived?
It's time.
I'm calling the Titans.
Hold on.
[Gasps] Wait!
[COLT]
Don't do it!
Please listen.
Falco accidentally got some
of the wine in his mouth.
He'll turn into a Titan!
Don't scream!
[Gasps]
What? Falco...
I'm your successor.
I'm inheriting the Beast Titan
so I can keep
Marley from sending
my whole family off
to Paradise, remember?
Colt, let me go! Run.
[COLT]
Even before you betrayed us,
I could never figure out
what you were thinking.
Maybe I don't know
the real you. But still!
I never could have
imagined you as
the kind of person who would
drag a child into your battles!
I'm not saying this
to try and make you
roll over and give up
on your plan.
Just hold off.
Let Falco get out of range
before you scream!
You can kill whoever
you need to after that.
Marleyan or Eldian.
I won't try to stop you.
But please!
Don't turn my little brother
into a monster!
Falco! We have to run!
Get away, Gabi!
Oh, Colt.
You care deeply for your
little brother, just like I do.
Don't do this.
I understand.
And I'm so sorry.
[ZEKE TITAN screams]
Run, Colt!
Run as far as you can get!
Your brother's
right here with you!
[ZEKE TITAN screams]
What happened?
They've all
been turned into Titans.
Hey. Ready the
Anti-Titan rifles!
[MARLEYAN SOLDIERS screaming]
Falco. Take him.
[Gasps]
[GABI]
Colt? Are you...?
[GABI sobs]
Falco?
[REINER] If I have to
keep fighting them both,
Eren will break free.
[REINER]
Will I have to be the one...
...to kill Falco?
Get back here!
[Gasps]
[REINER]
Falco. He's got my nape!
[Gasps]
[BOTH gasp]
That shot put him down for good.
Mission accomplished.
We're safe,
at least for a while.
[FLOCH] Dammit. Report!
Is anyone still alive?
[MAGATH]
That just leaves the Founder.
You've got no need
for that head.
And all we need is
your spinal fluid!
[Gasps]
We were just a little too slow.
Bring him down!
You can't win now.
This battle is over!
[REINER]
It's over?
[REINER] Eren can't use the
power of the Founder anymore.
That means our
mission is complete.
[REINER] So, then, the others
can take it from here, right?
I can undo the hardening
on my neck and let it happen.
[REINER] I can pass the
Armored Titan on... to Falco.
[Gasps]
[GALLIARD] It took everything I
had left to heal even this much.
But now, I can
make my death count.
I finally witnessed some of
my brother's memories.
You were the weakest
candidate in our unit,
but he tricked the brass
into making you a Warrior.
He screwed me out of it
to protect me.
[REINER]
Wait. You can't!
Don't do it, Porco!
I can let go of
whatever doubts I still had.
There's no denying
I deserved it more than you.
Huh? Galliard?
[REINER TITAN roars]
[Gasps]
[REINER]
No!
That trick I stole from Pieck
worked out alright for me.
I played dead long enough
to get their attention off me,
and you managed to
figure it out before them.
We can win this!
[REINER TITAN grunts]
Run! We're almost there!
[ZEKE] First of all, thanks,
for agreeing to meet with me.
I'm glad we're getting to talk.
You spoke with Yelena,
which means you know
where I stand.
The Eldian euthanization plan.
Do you support it or not?
Four years back,
something happened
to open one of our
dad's memories to me.
I relived his memory
of the night
he slaughtered the
royal family of the walls.
He crushed their little kids.
Smeared them like bugs.
I felt their bodies break.
If those kids had lived,
the royal family would've
reclaimed the Founder.
And bound to the vow
renouncing war,
humanity inside of the walls
would've lost any
chance of surviving.
The deaths of those children
are what allowed us to live.
Interesting.
So does that mean
you agree with him?
Think he did the right thing?
No. Our old man was mistaken.
[ZEKE gasps]
What's more, I think
it'd be fair to say
that I'm just another
mistake of his.
If the Eldians in this town
had never been born,
then none of them would
have to suffer and die
in the plan that you and I
are about to carry out.
This world was never
our birthright.
It's a hell to be saved from.
I'll do it, Zeke.
When the moment comes,
I'll bring 2,000 long years of
Titan domination to an end.
Until then, we both
keep moving forward.
All right? Brother?
[ZEKE]
Yeah. Precisely.
It's settled, then. Okay.
I want nothing more than
to shake your hand, Eren.
But, well, it's best if we don't
make physical contact yet.
So in lieu of that,
I'll give you this.
Eren. We're gonna save everyone.
Let it slip past me.
Guess I've gotten sluggish.
All that time in the hospital.
[GRISHA screams]
Where am I?
[ZEKE] The Coordinate,
where all Paths converge.
That's my theory.
When members of the royal
family inherited the Founder,
and exercised its power,
I think it transported them
to the plane we're on now.
Hello, Brother.
I've been waiting
for so long, Eren.
Sitting here alone in silence.
Years running together.
Wondering when you were
finally going to wake up.
Are you telling me that
we've been here for years?
[ZEKE] That's a hard
question to answer.
Everything that happens here
passes in an instant out there.
Gabi blew your head clean off,
but in those few moments
before your brain
shut down completely,
we made contact.
Our plan was a success.
The power of the Founding
Titan... is in our hands.
[EREN]
Someone's here.
She's not a threat to us.
Don't worry.
That's the Founder Ymir.
That little girl is Ymir?
How do you know?
That's the only thing
that makes any sense.
Who else would be wandering
around in a place like this?
[ZEKE]
The last time I came here,
she reformed my broken body from the ground
and returned me to life.
I suspect she's
been here for eons,
sculpting Titans from the earth.
Toiling away, spending years at
a time molding their bodies,
anytime we called
upon their power.
So she's been alone,
trapped in this empty place.
[ZEKE] Eren. You must
command the Founder Ymir.
At last, it's time
for us to fulfill
this dream we've been pursuing.
[Eren gasps] Those chains
around your neck.
I was starting to wonder
if you were ever
going to say
anything about that.
Well, even if it took a while,
I appreciate your concern.
These chains are what prevent me
from using her power
as I please.
They're the vow renouncing war.
As I thought,
you're the only one
with the ability to
move freely here,
which means you're
the only one capable of
taking command of
the Founder's power.
Do it, and fulfill
the dream we shared.
You, me, and Mister Ksaver.
Please. Save our world, Eren.
Eren?
Activate the power
of the Founder.
Do what we came here to do.
Have her take away
every Eldian's
ability to produce children!
Once that's done,
you can use the rumbling
to take out the Allied Forces.
Do you seriously believe
I'd euthanize the Eldian people?
Eren.
What kind of person
do you take me for?
I would never go along
with that repulsive plan.
Sorry, Brother.
I've been against you
from the start.
I was just playing along
to make sure I'd get this far.
[ZEKE]
This world will be a living hell
as long as the Eldian
people are part of it!
You have to do this now,
or else the bloodshed
will never stop.
This cycle of killing
we're caught up in
will just keep repeating
till the end of time!
So why? Why won't you end it?
Tell me!
'Cause I have a right to live
in the world I was born to.
[EREN]
Founder Ymir.
Grant me the power
to protect our people.
[ZEKE]
I suspected as much, Eren.
But I wanted to think that you,
of all people, would understand.
Can the scars that man left on
your mind really be that deep?
What's going on?
Why isn't Ymir obeying me?
[ZEKE] In the years I spent
waiting for you to wake up,
I learned quite a bit.
I learned that the Founder
can make anything.
She can even shape the earth
into these chains.
But only by the will of a person
with royal blood, like me.
And unlike the
Kings of the Walls
who had this power before me,
my mind was never tainted
by the ideology
of the first King.
Thanks to that,
during all the time
I spent here with the Founder
waiting for you to wake up,
I discovered a way to nullify
the vow renouncing war.
Ymir has the power to do
almost anything you can imagine,
but as a slave,
she lacks the will
to exercise that
power for herself.
She'll submit to anyone
who bears Eldian royal blood
in their veins and obey their
orders without question.
In short, the Founder's
power is mine alone.
That can't be.
You were no more than the key I needed to unlock that power, Eren.
I waited to hear
your true feelings,
and that was the right decision.
[EREN gasps]
This is not your fault.
It was our monster
of a father who
twisted you with
his brainwashing,
the same as he did with me.
Except, I had another father,
who saved me from that misery.
It might not have come to this
if you'd had somebody
to save you.
I give you my word that
I won't abandon you now.
I promise, I'll use the power
of the Founder to fix you!
You're wasting your breath.
I am going to save the world.
And I'll save it with you!
?Ending Song  ?
[NARRATOR] The elder brother
refuses to abandon the younger,
even after his rejection.
And together, they both bear
witness to a long-hidden truth.
Next episode:
"Memories of the Future."